<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Arecommender%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D10" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:recommender&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=10</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/kz5u9DrDcr9b+Xcurmz+p+peI1Y</id>
  <updated>2020-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">7985</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2004.03774v1</id>
    <updated>2020-04-08T02:11:55Z</updated>
    <published>2020-04-08T02:11:55Z</published>
    <title>Trust in Recommender Systems: A Deep Learning Perspective</title>
    <summary>  A significant remaining challenge for existing recommender systems is that
users may not trust the recommender systems for either lack of explanation or
inaccurate recommendation results. Thus, it becomes critical to embrace a
trustworthy recommender system. This survey provides a systemic summary of
three categories of trust-aware recommender systems: social-aware recommender
systems that leverage users' social relationships; robust recommender systems
that filter untruthful noises (e.g., spammers and fake information) or enhance
attack resistance; explainable recommender systems that provide explanations of
recommended items. We focus on the work based on deep learning techniques, an
emerging area in the recommendation research.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Manqing Dong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Feng Yuan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lina Yao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xianzhi Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiwei Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liming Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2004.03774v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2004.03774v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/0909.3472v2</id>
    <updated>2010-03-09T12:43:28Z</updated>
    <published>2009-09-18T15:54:51Z</published>
    <title>The Universal Recommender</title>
    <summary>  We describe the Universal Recommender, a recommender system for semantic
datasets that generalizes domain-specific recommenders such as content-based,
collaborative, social, bibliographic, lexicographic, hybrid and other
recommenders. In contrast to existing recommender systems, the Universal
Recommender applies to any dataset that allows a semantic representation. We
describe the scalable three-stage architecture of the Universal Recommender and
its application to Internet Protocol Television (IPTV). To achieve good
recommendation accuracy, several novel machine learning and optimization
problems are identified. We finally give a brief argument supporting the need
for machine learning recommenders.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jérôme Kunegis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alan Said</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Winfried Umbrath</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17 pages; typo and references fixed</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0909.3472v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/0909.3472v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/0908.3633v1</id>
    <updated>2009-08-25T15:30:34Z</updated>
    <published>2009-08-25T15:30:34Z</published>
    <title>Maximizing profit using recommender systems</title>
    <summary>  Traditional recommendation systems make recommendations based solely on the
customer's past purchases, product ratings and demographic data without
considering the profitability the items being recommended. In this work we
study the question of how a vendor can directly incorporate the profitability
of items into its recommender so as to maximize its expected profit while still
providing accurate recommendations. Our approach uses the output of any
traditional recommender system and adjust them according to item
profitabilities. Our approach is parameterized so the vendor can control how
much the recommendation incorporating profits can deviate from the traditional
recommendation. We study our approach under two settings and show that it
achieves approximately 22% more profit than traditional recommendations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Aparna Das</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Claire Mathieu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Ricketts</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0908.3633v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/0908.3633v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1312.1448v1</id>
    <updated>2013-12-05T06:50:30Z</updated>
    <published>2013-12-05T06:50:30Z</published>
    <title>Food Recommendation using Ontology and Heuristics</title>
    <summary>  Recommender systems are needed to find food items of ones interest. We review
recommender systems and recommendation methods. We propose a food
personalization framework based on adaptive hypermedia. We extend Hermes
framework with food recommendation functionality. We combine TF-IDF term
extraction method with cosine similarity measure. Healthy heuristics and
standard food database are incorporated into the knowledgebase. Based on the
performed evaluation, we conclude that semantic recommender systems in general
outperform traditional recommenders systems with respect to accuracy,
precision, and recall, and that the proposed recommender has a better F-measure
than existing semantic recommenders.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>M. A. El-Dosuky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Z. Rashad</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>T. T. Hamza</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. H. EL-Bassiouny</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1312.1448v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1312.1448v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1707.08913v1</id>
    <updated>2017-07-27T15:52:18Z</updated>
    <published>2017-07-27T15:52:18Z</published>
    <title>Multi-Stakeholder Recommendation: Applications and Challenges</title>
    <summary>  Recommender systems have been successfully applied to assist decision making
by producing a list of item recommendations tailored to user preferences.
Traditional recommender systems only focus on optimizing the utility of the end
users who are the receiver of the recommendations. By contrast,
multi-stakeholder recommendation attempts to generate recommendations that
satisfy the needs of both the end users and other parties or stakeholders. This
paper provides an overview and discussion about the multi-stakeholder
recommendations from the perspective of practical applications, available data
sets, corresponding research challenges and potential solutions.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yong Zheng</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Presented at the 2017 Workshop on Value-Aware and Multistakeholder
  Recommendation</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1707.08913v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1707.08913v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1302.6580v1</id>
    <updated>2013-02-26T20:55:42Z</updated>
    <published>2013-02-26T20:55:42Z</published>
    <title>Finding the Right Set of Users: Generalized Constraints for Group
  Recommendations</title>
    <summary>  Recently, group recommendations have attracted considerable attention. Rather
than recommending items to individual users, group recommenders recommend items
to groups of users. In this position paper, we introduce the problem of forming
an appropriate group of users to recommend an item when constraints apply to
the members of the group. We present a formal model of the problem and an
algorithm for its solution. Finally, we identify several directions for future
work.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kostas Stefanidis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Evaggelia Pitoura</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">PersDB 2012</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1302.6580v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1302.6580v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1507.08120v1</id>
    <updated>2015-07-29T12:44:49Z</updated>
    <published>2015-07-29T12:44:49Z</published>
    <title>Improving Reachability and Navigability in Recommender Systems</title>
    <summary>  In this paper, we investigate recommender systems from a network perspective
and investigate recommendation networks, where nodes are items (e.g., movies)
and edges are constructed from top-N recommendations (e.g., related movies). In
particular, we focus on evaluating the reachability and navigability of
recommendation networks and investigate the following questions: (i) How well
do recommendation networks support navigation and exploratory search? (ii) What
is the influence of parameters, in particular different recommendation
algorithms and the number of recommendations shown, on reachability and
navigability? and (iii) How can reachability and navigability be improved in
these networks? We tackle these questions by first evaluating the reachability
of recommendation networks by investigating their structural properties.
Second, we evaluate navigability by simulating three different models of
information seeking scenarios. We find that with standard algorithms,
recommender systems are not well suited to navigation and exploration and
propose methods to modify recommendations to improve this. Our work extends
from one-click-based evaluations of recommender systems towards multi-click
analysis (i.e., sequences of dependent clicks) and presents a general,
comprehensive approach to evaluating navigability of arbitrary recommendation
networks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Lamprecht</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Markus Strohmaier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Denis Helic</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1507.08120v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1507.08120v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1904.00672v1</id>
    <updated>2019-04-01T09:55:16Z</updated>
    <published>2019-04-01T09:55:16Z</published>
    <title>Enhancing the long-term performance of recommender system</title>
    <summary>  Recommender system is a critically important tool in online commercial system
and provide users with personalized recommendation on items. So far, numerous
recommendation algorithms have been made to further improve the recommendation
performance in a single-step recommendation, while the long-term recommendation
performance is neglected. In this paper, we proposed an approach called
Adjustment of Recommendation List (ARL) to enhance the long-term recommendation
accuracy. In order to observe the long-term accuracy, we developed an evolution
model of network to simulate the interaction between the recommender system and
user's behaviour. The result shows that not only long-term recommendation
accuracy can be enhanced significantly but the diversity of item in online
system maintains healthy. Notably, an optimal parameter n* of ARL existed in
long-term recommendation, indicating that there is a trade-off between keeping
diversity of item and user's preference to maximize the long-term
recommendation accuracy. Finally, we confirmed that the optimal parameter n* is
stable during evolving network, which reveals the robustness of ARL method.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Leyang Xue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peng Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>An Zeng</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1016/j.physa.2019.121731</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physa.2019.121731" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">16 pages, 10 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Physica A. 531.2019.121731</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1904.00672v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1904.00672v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.soc-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.soc-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1908.10171v1</id>
    <updated>2019-08-27T12:57:25Z</updated>
    <published>2019-08-27T12:57:25Z</published>
    <title>Improving End-to-End Sequential Recommendations with Intent-aware
  Diversification</title>
    <summary>  Sequential Recommendation (SRs) that capture users' dynamic intents by
modeling user sequential behaviors can recommend closely accurate products to
users. Previous work on SRs is mostly focused on optimizing the recommendation
accuracy, often ignoring the recommendation diversity, even though it is an
important criterion for evaluating the recommendation performance. Most
existing methods for improving the diversity of recommendations are not ideally
applicable for SRs because they assume that user intents are static and rely on
post-processing the list of recommendations to promote diversity. We consider
both recommendation accuracy and diversity for SRs by proposing an end-to-end
neural model, called Intent-aware Diversified Sequential Recommendation (IDSR).
Specifically, we introduce an Implicit Intent Mining module (IIM) into SRs to
capture different user intents reflected in user behavior sequences. Then, we
design an Intent-aware Diversity Promoting (IDP) loss to supervise the learning
of the IIM module and force the model to take recommendation diversity into
consideration during training. Extensive experiments on two benchmark datasets
show that IDSR significantly outperforms state-of-the-art methods in terms of
recommendation diversity while yielding comparable or superior recommendation
accuracy.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wanyu Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pengjie Ren</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fei Cai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maarten de Rijke</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1908.10171v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1908.10171v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1911.09872v1</id>
    <updated>2019-11-22T06:22:21Z</updated>
    <published>2019-11-22T06:22:21Z</published>
    <title>Privacy-Aware Recommendation with Private-Attribute Protection using
  Adversarial Learning</title>
    <summary>  Recommendation is one of the critical applications that helps users find
information relevant to their interests. However, a malicious attacker can
infer users' private information via recommendations. Prior work obfuscates
user-item data before sharing it with recommendation system. This approach does
not explicitly address the quality of recommendation while performing data
obfuscation. Moreover, it cannot protect users against private-attribute
inference attacks based on recommendations. This work is the first attempt to
build a Recommendation with Attribute Protection (RAP) model which
simultaneously recommends relevant items and counters private-attribute
inference attacks. The key idea of our approach is to formulate this problem as
an adversarial learning problem with two main components: the private attribute
inference attacker, and the Bayesian personalized recommender. The attacker
seeks to infer users' private-attribute information according to their items
list and recommendations. The recommender aims to extract users' interests
while employing the attacker to regularize the recommendation process.
Experiments show that the proposed model both preserves the quality of
recommendation service and protects users against private-attribute inference
attacks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ghazaleh Beigi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ahmadreza Mosallanezhad</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruocheng Guo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hamidreza Alvari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Nou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Huan Liu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1145/3336191.3371832</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3336191.3371832" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">The Thirteenth ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data
  Mining (WSDM 2020)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1911.09872v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1911.09872v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
